<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[log24]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.png</url><title>log24</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 02:19:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 02:19:33 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[2024 W19]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>So, I was trying to look for literature to write the introduction when I found out of this phenomenon called spin freezing, which if I am not mistaken is exactly what we are seeing.<br>I will dump my three days of research on this topic here to discuss them. I wrote this in English to make copy-pasting easier.<br>Key idea: Nobody knows how and why Pyrochlores exhibit a spin-glass transition when they have no quenched disorder.<br>I promise I will make a table eventually<br><br>From Wikipedia <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spin_glass" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spin_glass" target="_blank">Spin Glass</a> <br>Spin glasses are metastable because they are stuck in stable configurations other than the lowest-energy configuration.<br>One characteristic of spin glass systems is that, below the freezing temperature&nbsp; instances are trapped in a "non-ergodic" set of states: the system may fluctuate between several states, but cannot transition to other states of equivalent energy. Intuitively, one can say that the system cannot escape from deep minima of the hierarchically disordered&nbsp;energy landscape.<br><br>From <a class="internal-link" data-href="10.1103/PhysRevLett.74.2379" href="10.1103\PhysRevLett.74.2379" target="_self" rel="noopener">Frustration Induced Spin Freezing in a Site-Ordered Magnet: Gadolinium Gallium Garnet</a><br>Magnetically a spin-glass transition is characterized by decreasing magnetic susceptibility after a peak when the freezing temperature is approached. As the field  is increased, the peak is suppressed and shifted to lower temperatures. Apparently consistent with a spin glass transition.<br>In summary, they found spin-glass behaviour in GGG due to highly frustrated geometry. GGG is different from pyrochlores, and SGT in this material shows that it can occur in a geometrically frustrated system with minimal disorder. Typical spin glass models either have random exchange interactions or disoredered lattice sites.<br>They also cite ohter pyrocholres with spin-freezing behaviour Tb2Mo2O7 (Gaulin et. al. 1992), R2Mo2O7 (Raju et. al. 1992), and Y2Mn2O7 (Reimers et. al. 1991)<br>This is important because they show that SGT can be found in highly ordered lattices. They mention other stuff that I don't understand<br><br>From <a class="internal-link" data-href="10.1038/35092516" href="10.1038\35092516" target="_self" rel="noopener">How spin ice freezes (2001)</a> ...<br>It is found that Dy2Ti2O7 has a spin-glass transition, but different from others found before. Usually the field suppresses the peaks in susceptibility, but here it enhances  and suppresses  for all temperatures below the freezing temperature. They say<br>"The spin-freezing in Dy2Ti2O7 represents a new form of spinfreezing. Rather than the dynamic freezing associated with relaxations over a wide range of length and time scales as in manifestly disordered systems, spin ice shows macroscopic behaviour that is analogous to glassiness (that is, freezing observed at different temperatures on different timescales), but predominantly associated with a single relaxation mode. This Ænding is consistent with Dy2Ti2O7 being a pure material: the frustration arises from the local geometry of the lattice and not the large-scale disorder typically associated with dynamic spin-freezing in magnetic systems."<br><br>From <a class="internal-link" data-href="10.1103/PhysRevB.69.064414" href="10.1103\PhysRevB.69.064414" target="_self" rel="noopener">Low-temperature spin freezing in the Dy2Ti2O7 spin ice (2004)</a> <br>This is a continuation, with same leading author.<br>The difference between the spin freezing in Dy2Ti2O7 and that in spin glasses is perhaps not surprising, since origin of the spin ice state is purely geometrical and does not involve the structural and chemical disorder traditionally associated with glassiness in magnetic materials.<br><br>From  <a class="internal-link" data-href="10.1103/PhysRevLett.109.247201" href="10.1103\PhysRevLett.109.247201" target="_self" rel="noopener">Nonconventional Spin Glass Transition in a Chemically Ordered Pyrochlore</a><br>"In general, a spin glass state arises in a material where the combination of randomness and frustration prevents the development of long range magnetic order. However, in some materials, such as Tb2Mo2O7 or, Y2Mo2O7 or, Gd3Ga5O12, no evidence of chemical disorder is found."<br>Alch no entendí nada que lo hace nonconventional<br><br>From <a class="internal-link" data-href="10.1103/PhysRevLett.124.087201" href="10.1103\PhysRevLett.124.087201" target="_self" rel="noopener">Spin-Orbital Glass Transition in a Model of a Frustrated Pyrochlore Magnet without Quenched Disorder</a><br>One of the main characteristics of spin glasses lies on the randomness of the system's parameters, i.e. quenched disorder. Some of the previous papers already showed that intrinsic disorder was not necessary, and spin-glass states can arise in intrinsically ordered systems. This phenomena is still not yet understood. In this paper, the authors develop a model for Y2Mo2O7 that can exhibit a glass transition.<br>They consider two degrees of freedom: spins and orbitals which are coupled through a Jahn-Teller lattice distortion which modifies the super exchange interactions between the spins dynamically. <br>They mention  paper (19 in their cites) that shows that Y2Mo2O7 presents lattice distortions, i.e. Mo ions are slightly displaced towards or away of the centers of the Mo4 tetrahedra. <br>Their model is a Heisenberg model, and a lattice distortion term, that is an Ising like model, spin sign represents moving the Mo ions inward or outward. The spin exchange interaction depend on the angle of the Mo-O-Mo bond, and varies in such a way that the sign of the interaction can change.<br>"The existence of the SG transition itself is already established in Y2Mo2O7 and its families, and although its origin has not been understood, a recent analysis showed that the lattice distortions possibly play a certain role in the glass transition."<br><br>From <a class="internal-link" data-href="10.1038/nphys1028" href="10.1038\nphys1028" target="_self" rel="noopener">Spin-glass order induced by dynamic frustration</a><br>Spin-glass order has been found in URh2Ge2 (ref. 4) and PrAu2Si2 (ref. 2), both with the same structure, however, it was later shown that spin freezing in URh2Ge2 resulted from local disorder as an AF GS could be reached after removing the source of the disorder. However, the spin-glass order in PrAu2Si2 is very robust and appears in the purest samples.<br>Just for reference, this compound is an induced moment system, hence magnetic moments have some lifetime.<br>In second order phase transitions correlation length diverges. The authors suggest that in this compound the divergence in the magnetic correlation length is suppressed by dynamic fluctuations that limit the lifetime of induced moments and introduce magnetic site and exchange disorder. This scenario resembles the 'avoided criticality' from the theory of structural glass transitions by Tarjus et al. "In their review, they argue that many glasses are close to a conventional second-order phase transition, but that frustration prevents the divergence of the correlation length."<br><br>From <a class="internal-link" data-href="10.1088/0953-8984/20/32/325201" href="10.1088\0953-8984\20\32\325201" target="_self" rel="noopener">Unconventional spin glass behavior in the cubic pyrochlore Mn2Sb2O7</a><br>"The resulting material has an unconventional spin glass state at&nbsp;&nbsp;K, in the absence of detectable site disorder or a structural phase transition."<br>This material is another example of a spin glass phase induced by frustration effects inherent from the pyrochlore structure. The possible explanation could take the form of local deformations in the lattice.<br><br>There are more papers that report this unconventional spin-glass ordering in pyrochlores. I found this review <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2004.12.084" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2004.12.084" target="_blank">Frustrated rare earth magnetism: Spin glasses, spin liquids and spin ices in pyrochlore oxides</a><br><br><br>From what I read, spin-glass ordering in non disordered systems can (more or less) be explained by induced disorder by something intrinsic to the system, but when fluctuating, produces quenched disorder.<br>The general question would be: why does this behaviour arises in Artificial Colloidal ice? <br>
<br>
Thermal Ice (Already rejected)<br>
My first conjecture lied on thermal ice itself. I remembered from the poster that the system kind of reached the AF ground state. So I thought of something like 'thermal induced disorder'.<br>
However, I remembered that we already ran simulations at 1K, so this idea makes no sense.

<br>
I have no other ideas xd

]]></description><link>2024-w19.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">2024 W19.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 02:10:19 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>